Roshan Bajgain

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Email | GitHub | Twitter | Portfolio | LinkedIn | Angelist

SUMMARY

Creative Web Developer dedicated to developing and optimizing interactive, user-friendly, and feature-rich websites. Leverage analytical skills and strong attention to detail in order to deliver original and efficient web solutions, provide technical knowledge and expertise, and build new websites from start to finish. Excellent team worker with in-depth knowledge of development tools.

SKILLS

Front-end: JavaScript, React, Redux, HTML5, CSS3

Back-end: Ruby, Rails, MySQL, Postgres

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring

EXPERIENCE

Highlighted Personal Projects

Full-stack Web Developer

10/2021 - Present

Mastered intermediate and advanced topics in full-stack development (including Ruby, Rails, Git, and DS&A challenges) while building multiple full-stack projects both independently and via pair programming.

Freelance work:

My portfolio: The portfolio project is my personal portfolio website, including my details, the previous project works, and a contact form. This website is completely responsive for mobile and desktop.

Built with: (HTML, CSS, and JavaScript)

<u>Space travels</u>: Space Traveler's Hub is a single-page web application that fetches rockets, and missions from the SpaceX API. Users can book and cancel their reservations for rockets and missions. The application has three pages Rockets/Missions/MY Profile, My Profile page shows the list of reserved rockets and missions.

• Built with: (React, redux)

<u>Motorcycle Booking</u>: This app is the front-end version of the Motorcycle booking services. Built with react exclusively. The app fetches data from the API. The app allows you to see the details of the Motorcycle. You can reserve the best motorcycle of your choice and have a test drive.

Built with: (React, Redux, and Ruby and Rails)

Microverse

Technical Support Engineer (Code reviewer)

02/2022 - Present

- Provide technical help to the junior Developer and guide them in their project.
- Check the quality of the project and provide feedback for better improvement.
- Provided advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program.

Mentor (Volunteer)

01/2022 - Present

- Mentored junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews, yielding a 100% satisfaction rate from mentees and instructors.
- Provided advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program, enhancing student retention by 23% from the previous year.
- Proposed improvements to code to boost code quality and overall performance of the students.

EDUCATION

Microverse 10/2021 - Present

Remote Full-stack Web Development Program, Full Time

• Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.

• Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

Vedas Campus 01/2022 - Present

BCA: Bachelor in Computer Application (BCA) is a four-year undergraduate degree that deals with Information Technology (IT) and Computer Applications.